It was
-4°C this morning, a frosty
reminder that it's
time to scour the
closet shelves for
warm socks and
gloves.  The days are so
short and the light
fades so quickly.
The solstice is approaching, and I
stare at the flickering
flame of the candle,
reflecting on the
darkness and how to
keep bright
thoughts at such a time.
Yesterday I decided to go through
my box of
memories.  When I was
a child, my father
sent it to me while he was
in the
Middle East.
It is mostly
filled with letters—
responses to
countless messages
I have sent since I
learned to
write.  As a child, I
really wanted to be
a writer and
wrote to all my
favorite authors
asking for advice, and
they often
supported this
nine-year-old
girl
by answering the
letters.  I spent
so many years
writing, reading,
and filling
countless pages with
my stories and
poems.  I still
hope to write
a few books in
my lifetime, but
fortunately my
obsession is now
balanced by other
interests.  When it
comes to
your hopes and
dreams, it becomes quite
easy to realize that
there is no need to
rush.  You have a
whole life to
accomplish them.  When
you look at your goals
and aspirations from
this angle, you can breathe a
sigh of relief and
start
enjoying
each day,
gradually taking steps
towards who you want to
become or what you want to
do.  Life suddenly
slows down.  The days
are getting longer and
filled with
details.  The future is
still important, but
it is no longer the sole
object of all your
efforts.
I used to
focus too much on
the future,
obsessing over the
unknown, giving
it power over my
present.  What
will happen to this
planet and its people
?  Will
this year's trials ever end?  Will
I achieve my dreams?
Is the future really
as dark as
people say?  When I get
so desperate, I
forget what I'm
capable of right now.  I
look into the eyes of my
young students and see there the
hope for a happy
life.  And suddenly I
feel ashamed for
not being an
example of light for them.
If we cannot
support our
children, inspire them
to become better and
love this
planet more, to take action
instead of
giving in to despair, we
lose sight of that
same flame.  I am to
blame for this
confusion, because
sometimes it is easier
to retreat than
to ask myself: "How
can I help?"
Each of us can
become a source of hope,
act decisively, and most
importantly, choose
joy in our
lives.  Become an
example to those
who have despaired and
turned away from the
light.  As
the solstice approaches and a
new radiance comes into the world,
I implore you
to hold on to it.
May it fill
your soul with wonder and
possibilities for a
future
full of beauty,
warmth, and kindness.
There will be those who do not
want to go with
you, and that is their choice
.  But perhaps choosing
hope is a sacred
path that leads to a
life you could never have
imagined.